Matt Lim

San Francisco, California, US | +1 (925) 639-4567 | mattlim33@gmail.com mattlim.me | github.com/arcticmatt | linkedin.com/in/itsmlim

Software Engineer and Founder

I've been working as a software engineer for the last 6 years across full stack web development, systems engineering, and product infra. My strength is building polished and scalable products, often from zero to one. Outside of "work-work," I love building side projects, some of which are listed below (see my website for the rest).

Work Experience

Co-Founder and CTO, Formfunction

Jun 2021 - Jun 2023

- Raised a \$4.7M seed round from firms including Variant Fund and Pear VC.
- Built an NFT marketplace where creators could sell their digital art. Used React and Relay on the frontend, Express.js, GraphQL, and Postgres on the backend, and Rust for the Solana programs. Processed \$5 million in volume and made over \$200,000 in revenue in the first year.
- Hired and led a team of 4 engineers.

Senior Software Engineer, Meta/Facebook

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

- Full stack lead for a team in New Product Experimentation focused on social activism. Built a web app from zero to one that let people share and discover causes they care about, using React and GraphQL.
- AR/VR systems engineer. Designed and implemented a communication protocol that worked over Bluetooth,
 TCP, and STP. It was written in C++ and used for prototyping a number of new headsets.
- Product infra engineer in Integrity, led team of 4. Built a platformized way for developers to enable reps to
 <u>customize their experiences</u> (e.g. blurring graphic images) using React and GraphQL. Led migration of millions
 of actions per day (e.g. "delete this content") from Haskell to a new framework written in Hack.

Projects

Harken 2023

- Built <u>Harken</u>, a spaced repetition flashcard app that's a better version of Anki, using React/GraphQL/Express.
- Built the <u>Harken Chrome extension</u>, which lets you quiz yourself on content from any article on the internet by using GPT-4 to generate questions with a single click.

Minymon 2021

- Minymons are pets that live on your website and can answer common questions, interact with your visitors, and build your brand. Built with React, GraphQL, and Express.
- Was the #4 product of the day on Product Hunt and has generated \$3,000 in revenue.

Psychedelics Anonymous

2021

 Developed and deployed four ERC-721 smart contracts for the Psychedelics Anonymous NFT project. The four collections sold out in ~1 week and generated \$10 million in revenue.

See <u>mattlim.me</u> for more of my projects.

Skills

Programming Languages: (Expert) JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, (Experienced) Python, (Familiar) C++ **Technologies**: (Expert) React, GraphQL, Relay, Express.js (Experienced) Next.js, Postgres, Firebase

Education

California Institute of Technology

Jun 2013 – Jun 2017

- B.S in Computer Science, Minor in English
- 4.0 GPA
- TA for EE150, CS156a, CS122, CS156b